Fadhil

fadhilc97@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Website | Batam, Indonesia

Professional Summary

The professional software developer with 5+ years experience to solve the business problem. Also have been as educator who like to share my knowledge and experiences about digital literacy, especially about programming fundamentals for 1.5 years experience. Now working as Full-stack Developer in INCIT to develop assessment platform that help industrial transformation for their clients. A technology enthusiast with a passion for staying current and leveraging innovation to solve real-world challenges and support business growth.

Technical Skills

Python, TypeScript, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Odoo (ERP), Express.js, React, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Nest.js, Prisma.js, Drizzle ORM

Work Experience

International Centre for Industrial Transformation (INCIT) - Batam, Indonesia (Hybrid)

- November 2024 present as Full-stack Developer (Full-time)
 - o Create and integrate the APIs based on the requirements using Nest.js
 - Payment and invoicing services integration with Stripe, Google Pay, Apple Pay, and Xero
 - File storage services integration with AWS S3 and GCP Storage
- November 2022 November 2024 as Front-end Developer (Full-time)
 - Implement the UI/UX design with friendly usage and responsive design
 - Integrate backend APIs that already created with Backend Developer

Software Engineer (Full-time)

PT. Tigernix Solutions Indonesia - Batam, Indonesia

March 2020 - August 2022 (2 years 6 months)

- Develop and extend existing features in ERP application
- Provide data migration before live production
- Deployment setup using AWS EC2
- Create auto-backup database and attachment in server production with cron job and shell script

Substitute Teacher (Part-time)

SMK Multistudi High School - Batam, Indonesia

August 2019 - December 2019 (5 months)

- Provide materials, examination questions and evaluation for Web and Mobile subject
- As a participant companion to participate the "LKS 2019" (student skill competition) Web and Technology competition Riau Island Province level for school representative.

IT Staff (Internship)

PT. Multi Kreasi Sinergia - Batam, Indonesia

July 2018 - March 2019 (9 months)

- Handle the "Madebyme" makerspace
- Instructor of coding for kids
- Explore and prototyping related to robotic and IoT

Education

Batam State Polytechnic

Diploma Degree in Informatics Engineering (GPA: 3.79)

• Organization: Batam Linux User Group as Member of Programming Division